Guide to the Sherman Kent Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- WRITINGS, 1930-1976, undated; Series II; 7.75; (19 boxes)
  - Books Published
    - Writing History
      - Draft: "Why Study and Write History?" pp.1-97, 143-229, undated (Box 31, Folder 164-165)
      - Chapters 1-6, undated (Box 32, Folder 166-172)
      - "Draft #1", undated (Box 32, Folder 173)
      - Fragments, undated (Box 32, Folder 174-175)
      - Incomplete, undated (Box 32, Folder 176)
      - Introduction--draft, undated (Box 32, Folder 177)
      - "Original #1", undated (Box 33, Folder 178)
      - Notes, undated (Box 33, Folder 179)
      - Commentary, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 180)
  - Books Unpublished
    - "Buffalo Blocks"
      - Cuisenaire elementary manual, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 181)
      - Cuisenaire manual, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 182)
      - Cuisenaire set, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 183)
      - Draft, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 184-188)
      - Draft--manual, [1970] (Box 33, Folder 189)
      - Manual, Sets I, II, undated (Box 34, Folder 190)
      - Manuscript for Set III, 1970 January (Box 34, Folder 191)
      - Manual, Set IV, 1970 January-June (Box 34, Folder 192)
      - Manuals, Sets IV-VI, VIa, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 193-196)
      - Printed manuals, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 197-199)
      - Printed material, 1070 October (Box 34, Folder 200)
    - "Gold and Opals"
      - Chapters 1-15: preliminary version, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 201-202)
      - Chapters 1-14, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 203-204)
      - Chapters 1-14: xerox copy, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 205-206)
      - Chapters 1-14: complete copy, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 207)
      - Chapters 1-14: ribbon copy, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 208)
      - Complete copy, 1975 November 12 (Box 36, Folder 209)
      - Notes, undated (Box 36, Folder 210)
  - Speeches
    - Yale Class of 1928, [1930] (Box 36, Folder 211)
    - "French Foreign Policy," Rotary Club, 1934 June 5 (Box 36, Folder 212)
    - "The Historian in Time of Trouble: The Age of Metternich," American Historical Association
      - Copy as read, 1940 December (Box 36, Folder 213)
      - Preliminary writing, 1940-1941 (Box 36, Folder 214)
      - Rough drafts, 1940-1941 (Box 36, Folder 215)
      - Polished drafts, 1940-1941 (Box 36, Folder 216)
      - Approved draft, 1941 (Box 36, Folder 217)
      - Final draft, 1941 (Box 36, Folder 218)
      - Notes taken during meeting, 1941 December 27 (Box 36, Folder 219)
      - Talk by E. H. Harbison, 1941 December 27 (Box 36, Folder 220)
      - Short version, [1942] (Box 36, Folder 221)
    - Thacher School closing exercises, 1941 June 13 (Box 36, Folder 222)
    - "Capability Analysis," National War College, 1946 September 27 (Box 36, Folder 223)
    - "France," National War College: speech, lecture outlines, notes, supplemental material, 1946 November 1 (Box 36, Folder 224)
    - National War College, 1946 (Box 37, Folder 225)
    - "Leninism and Stalinism," National War College, 1946 (Box 37, Folder 226)
    - "Strategic Intelligence," National War College, 1947 January 6 (Box 37, Folder 227)
    - "Current Political Affairs," National War College: with George Kennan and Robert Linn, 1947 January 10 (Box 37, Folder 228)
    - "Conflicting Ideologies," National War College, 1947 October 3 (Box 37, Folder 229)
    - National War College, 1948 October 8 (Box 37, Folder 230)
    - Institute for Religious and Social Study, 1949 January 18 (Box 37, Folder 231)
    - "Intelligence and Foreign Policy," Berkeley Forum, 1949 March 3 (Box 37, Folder 232)
    - "World Situation Demands Better Strategic Intelligence for America," Yale Interprets the News, 1949 June 5 (Box 37, Folder 233)
    - "Strategic Intelligence," Bradwell's outfit, 1949 June 6 (Box 37, Folder 234)
    - "New Haven Election of 1949," League of Women Voters, 1949 October 24 (Box 37, Folder 235)
    - "Daumier and the July Monarchy," Grolier Club
      - Drafts, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 236)
      - Program, typescript, 1949 December 20 (Box 37, Folder 237)
    - Foote School graduation, Circa 1949 (Box 37, Folder 238)
    - "Intelligence," Air War College, Maxwell Air Force Base, 1950 February 28 (Box 37, Folder 239)
    - "Strategic Intelligence and National Security," A.A.V.W., 1950 April 28 (Box 37, Folder 240)
    - United States Naval Academy, 1950 October 3 (Box 37, Folder 241)
    - "Imp Pol Phils," National War College, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 242)
    - Introductions, Americans for Democratic Action Meeting, 1950 (Box 37, Folder 243)
    - "The Nature of Today's Important Isms," National War College, [1950] (Box 37, Folder 244)
    - "Democracy and Communism, Competing Ideologies," United States Naval Academy; National War College, 1951 September 18; September 26 (Box 37, Folder 245)
    - National Intelligence Orientation #2, 1955 May 3 (Box 37, Folder 246)
    - William L. Langer testimonial dinner, 1957 December 28 (Box 37, Folder 247)
    - Office of National Estimates party, 1960 December 9 (Box 37, Folder 248)
    - Retirement dinner, 1967 December 29 (Box 37, Folder 249)
    - "Mid Career Valedictory", 1968 March 8 (Box 37, Folder 250)
    - Commonwealth Club of California, 1969 July 5 (Box 37, Folder 251)
    - "Use of Intelligence in Statecraft," Defense Intelligence School, 1969 December 4 (Box 37, Folder 252)
    - "Ests," Foreign Service Institute Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy, [1969-1970] (Box 37, Folder 253)
    - "A Career in Intelligence," C.I.A. trainees, 1970 January 5, 1971 January 11, 1973 March 5 (Box 37, Folder 254)
    - F.B.I.S. staff, 1970 February 5 (Box 37, Folder 255)
    - Jim Cooley's departure, 1970 May (Box 37, Folder 256)
    - "Estimative Words," Defense Intelligence School, 1970 October 14 (Box 37, Folder 257)
    - Warrenton, 1970 October 19 (Box 37, Folder 258)
    - "Role of Intelligence in Policy Making," Defense Intelligence School, 1970 November 24 (Box 37, Folder 259)
    - "The Warning Business," Defense Intelligence School (not used), 1970 November 24 (Box 37, Folder 260)
    - "The Subjective Factor in an Estimate", 1970 December 3 (Box 37, Folder 261)
    - "The Raw Material of National Intelligence Estimates and the Way It Is Handled--The Case of N.I.E. 85-3-62," Defense Intelligence School, 1971 January 28 (Box 37, Folder 262)
    - "Aspects of Intelligence Producer Consumer Relationship," Defense Intelligence School, 1971 February 19, 1972 March 31, 1973 April 2 (Box 37, Folder 263)
    - "Aspects of the Intelligence Producer/Consumer Relationship", 1971 February 26 (Box 38, Folder 264)
    - "The Relationship Between Producers and Consumers of High Level Speculative Intelligence", 1973 September 17 (Box 38, Folder 265)
    - "The Philosophy of Intelligence," Defense Intelligence School, 1971 June (Box 38, Folder 266)
    - "Some Philosophical Considerations of the Intelligence Business," Defense Intelligence School, 1971 November (Box 38, Folder 267)
    - Defense Intelligence School, 1971 November 23 (Box 38, Folder 268)
    - Unidentified (not given), 1971 (Box 38, Folder 269)
    - "Nature and Significance of Strategic Intelligence," Defense Intelligence School, 1972 January 3 (Box 38, Folder 270)
    - "Historical Considerations of the National Intelligence Estimate," Defense Intelligence School, 1972 November (Box 38, Folder 271)
    - "National Intelligence Estimates and the N.S.C.", 1973 September 17 (Box 38, Folder 272)
    - "Historical Considerations of the National Estimate," Defense Intelligence School, 1973 November 28 (Box 38, Folder 273)
    - "Nature and Significance of Strategic Intelligence (Perspectives on National Security Intelligence)," Defense Intelligence School, 1975 February 20 (Box 38, Folder 274)
    - Foote School, undated (Box 38, Folder 275)
    - Osterweis Group, undated (Box 38, Folder 276)
    - Delta Kappa Epsilon, undated (Box 38, Folder 277)
    - To the male cook, undated (Box 38, Folder 278)
    - "Intelligence of Capabilities", undated (Box 38, Folder 279)
  - [Lecture notes?]
    - Painting, general, undated (Box 38, Folder 280)
    - French painting, 17th and 18th centuries, undated (Box 38, Folder 281)
    - French painting, romanticism, undated (Box 38, Folder 282)
    - French painting, rococo style, undated (Box 38, Folder 283)
    - French painting, imperial style, undated (Box 38, Folder 284)
    - 96e Congrès nationâle des sociétés savantes, undated (Box 38, Folder 285)
    - French painting, impressionist and post-impressionists, undated (Box 38, Folder 286)
    - Painting, since 1906 (incomplete), undated (Box 38, Folder 287)
    - Painting, modern art, undated (Box 38, Folder 288)
- SUBJECT FILES, 1928-1974; Series III; 5; (13 boxes)
  This series is arranged by topic in alphabetical order. Files for each topic are also arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Buffalo Blocks
    - General correspondence, 1968-1971 Jul, 1971 November-1972 November (Box 39, Folder 1-13)
    - Correspondence with Arnco/Jayem, 1970 May-1971 January (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence with Crocker National Bank, 1971 October-November (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence with Dakin, 1971 September-1972 April (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence with Hirschmugl, 1970 January-September (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence with Kaplin/Instructor, 1972 November-1973 June (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence with Loehrer, 1970 May-September (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Cuisenaire account, 1970 January-Oct, 1971, undated (Box 40, Folder 20-23)
    - Patent/trademark/copyright information, 1970-1972 (Box 40, Folder 24-26)
    - Unfinished business and correspondence re bookkeeping, 1970 October-1971 February (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - French History
    - Résumés, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 28)
    - Economic statistics, 1837-1841, undated (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - Economic statistics, 1830's, undated (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Electoral lists, undated (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - July Monarchy, undated (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - Villèle, notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - Intelligence
    - Africa, 1941 November-1942 December (Box 41, Folder 34)
    - Atomic Energy Commission film, 1971 February (Box 41, Folder 35)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 1945 September-1950 December (Box 41, Folder 36)
    - Cuban missile crisis, 1962 August-1963 March (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - Dulles, Allen
      - Clippings, miscellaneous, 1954 March-1973 January (Box 41, Folder 38)
      - Clippings, Craft of Intelligence, 1959 September-1963 April (Box 41, Folder 39)
    - ECA national product tables, Circa 1950 (Box 41, Folder 40)
    - Economic estimates, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 41)
    - Intelligence and policy, Circa 1965 (Box 41, Folder 42)
    - Invisible Government, 1964 June (Box 41, Folder 43)
    - Marchetti, Vincent, 1971 October-1974 June (Box 41, Folder 44)
    - Memoranda and notes, 1945 September-1951 Dec, 1963 May-1974 May (Box 41, Folder 45-46)
    - Memoranda and notes, undated (Box 42, Folder 47)
    - Paris summit, 1960 May (Box 42, Folder 48)
    - Printed material, 1942-1951, 1956-1965, 1967, 1971-1974 (Box 42, Folder 49-57)
    - Research and analysis branch, 1943-1945 (Box 43, Folder 58)
    - Soviet Union, 1951-1970 (Box 43, Folder 59)
    - Special Operations Research Office, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 60)
    - Special weapons orientation course, undated (Box 43, Folder 61)
    - Super Spies, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 62)
  - National War College
    - Board of Consultants report, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 63)
    - Class lists, 1946-1947 (Box 43, Folder 64)
    - Course content, 1946-1947 (Box 43, Folder 65)
    - Course critique, 1946, undated (Box 43, Folder 66)
    - Course outline, 1946-1947, 1947 November (Box 43, Folder 67-68)
    - Curriculum proposed with critique, 1945 (Box 43, Folder 69)
    - Directories, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 70)
    - Lecturers' information, undated (Box 43, Folder 71)
    - Printed material, 1947 (Box 43, Folder 72)
    - Readings for prospective students, 1947 (Box 43, Folder 73)
    - Schedules, 1946-1947 (Box 43, Folder 74-75)
    - Spring trip, 1947 (Box 43, Folder 76)
    - Student biographies and class and faculty lists, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 77-78)
  - New Haven 1949 election
    - Background material, 1947-1949 (Box 43, Folder 79)
    - Democratic Town Committee literature, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 80)
    - Kent campaign for alderman, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 81)
    - Richard Lee's press releases, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 82)
    - Voter lists, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 83)
  - Yale teaching files
    - Course materials
      - History 10, 1929-1941 (Box 44, Folder 84-92)
      - History 10a, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 93)
      - History 10b, 1949-1950 (Box 44, Folder 94-95)
      - History 12, 1934-1939 (Box 44, Folder 96-98)
      - History 33, 1934 (Box 44, Folder 99)
      - History 35, 1939-1940 (Box 44, Folder 100-101)
      - History 54, 1950, undated (Box 44, Folder 102)
      - History 54a, 1940-1950, undated (Box 44, Folder 103-104)
      - History 55, 1947-1950, undated (Box 45, Folder 105-113)
      - History 154, 1948-1949, undated (Box 46, Folder 114-119)
      - Course materials, miscellaneous, 1947, undated (Box 46, Folder 120)
    - Grades
      Gradebooks are restricted until January 1, 2035.
      - Unidentified course, 1937-1938 (Box 47, Folder 121)
      - History 10, 1928-1940, 1948-1949 (Box 47, Folder 122-131)
      - History 10b, 1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 132)
      - History 12, 1934-1938 (Box 47, Folder 133-136)
      - History 33, 1933-1934 (Box 47, Folder 137)
      - History 55, 1948-1950 (Box 47, Folder 138-140)
    - Students' papers
      - History 147, 1938-1939, undated (Box 48, Folder 141-144)
      - History 154, 1947-1948 (Box 48, Folder 145-147)
      - History 154, 1948-1949, undated (Box 49, Folder 148-154)
      - History 155, 1950 (Box 49, Folder 155)
      - History 156, 1950 (Box 49, Folder 156)
      - Unidentified history courses, 1935-1938 (Box 49, Folder 157-158)
      - Unidentified history courses, 1939-1940, 1947-1949 (Box 50, Folder 159-166)
      - Unidentified history courses, 1949-1950, undated (Box 51, Folder 167-173)
      - Unidentified history graduate courses, 1938, 1948 (Box 51, Folder 174)
- PERSONAL PAPERS, 1763-1978; Series IV; 2.75; (7 boxes)
  Materials in this series are arranged by record type and are listed in alphabetical order.
  - Autographs, 1763, 1836, 1880 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Awards and certificates: general, 1945, 1963-1967 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Awards: National Civil Service League, 1961 March (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Awards: President's Award for Distinguished Federal Civilian Service, 1967 August (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Biographical data, 1941-1946, 1950, 1963-1967, 1980, 1986 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Business cards, undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Calendars, 1948, 1971 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Christmas lists, 1962-1978 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: Kent, 1947-1950, 1956-1977 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Clippings: A Boy and a Pig, but Mostly Horses, 1974 October-1975 March (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Clippings: Strategic Intelligence for American World Policy, 1949-1950 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Diaries, 1918-1920 (Box 52, Folder 12-14)
  - Diaries, 1921-1922 (Box 53, Folder 15-16)
  - Diary and notes from the Sorbonne, 1926 June-August (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Diary, 1931 May-1932 October (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Identification papers, passports, licenses, and membership cards, 1927-1972 (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Kent family papers and clippings, 1803, 1876, 1890, 1897, 1903, 1931, 1947-1951, 1969-1976 (Box 53, Folder 20)
  - Memoirs: transcripts of tapes, Chapters 1-3, undated (Box 53, Folder 21)
  - Memoirs: draft, early years, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 22)
  - Memoirs, undated (Box 53, Folder 23-26)
  - Memoirs, undated (Box 54, Folder 27-30)
  - Photographs
    - Intelligence: Calcutta, Korea, China, 1959 October-1966 February (Box 54, Folder 31)
    - Intelligence: ceremonies, receptions, group portraits, 1956-1969 (Box 54, Folder 32-34)
    - Personal: family, class reunions, etc., 1887, 1938, 1960, 1967-1972, undated (Box 54, Folder 35)
    - Portraits of Sherman Kent, 1942, 1952, 1961, 1966, 1972, undated (Box 54, Folder 36)
    - Associates, 1924-1930, 1945-1947, 1967, undated (Box 55, Folder 37)
  - Programs and memorabilia from engagements, 1934, 1964-1974, undated (Box 55, Folder 38)
  - Student papers
    - Class notes
      - Anthropology 10b, 1925 February-May (Box 55, Folder 39)
      - Art 10: Pictorial Art, 1925 October-1926 May (Box 55, Folder 40)
      - Biology 10, 1925 October-1926 January (Box 55, Folder 41)
      - Biology: Organic Evolution, 1925 October-1926 January (Box 55, Folder 42)
      - Biology: Heredity and Evolution, 1925 February-March (Box 55, Folder 43)
      - Biology: Organic Evolution, 1926 February-March (Box 55, Folder 44)
      - Economics 10, 1923 October-November (Box 55, Folder 45)
      - English: Chaucer, 1925 October-1926 June (Box 55, Folder 46-47)
      - English, Sophomore, undated (Box 55, Folder 48)
      - History 10, 1923-1924 (Box 55, Folder 49)
      - History 141, undated (Box 55, Folder 50)
      - History 150, undated (Box 55, Folder 51)
      - History 152, undated (Box 55, Folder 52)
      - History: Contemporary Europe, 1926 February-June (Box 55, Folder 53)
      - History: French Revolution and Napoleon, 1925 October-1926 January (Box 55, Folder 54)
      - History: French Revolution and Napoleon, 1926 January (Box 56, Folder 55)
      - History: Middle Ages, 1924 October-1925 May (Box 56, Folder 56)
      - History: unidentified, undated (Box 56, Folder 57)
      - Physics 10, 1922-1923 (Box 56, Folder 58)
      - Political Science 10: Government, 1925 October-1926 June (Box 56, Folder 59-61)
      - Political Science: American Politics, 1924 October-1925 January, 1925 November-1926 January (Box 56, Folder 62-63)
      - Political Science: Socialism, 1925 February-Mar, 1926 February (Box 56, Folder 64-65)
      - Political Science: Socialism and Social Reform, 1926 February-June (Box 56, Folder 66)
      - Psychology 10, 1923 October-1924 June (Box 56, Folder 67)
    - Other course materials
      - Compositions, 1927, undated (Box 57, Folder 68-74)
      - Exams, 1926-1927 (Box 57, Folder 75)
      - Travel memorabilia, 1942-1944 (Box 57, Folder 76)
  - Travel notes
    - Egypt, Netherlands, 1954 (Box 57, Folder 77)
    - Guatemala, 1955 (Box 57, Folder 78)
    - Europe, 1956, 1958 (Box 57, Folder 79-80)
    - Far East, India, Egypt, London, 1959 October-December (Box 57, Folder 81)
    - Summit trip, 1960 May-June (Box 57, Folder 82)
    - Latin America, 1961 April-May (Box 57, Folder 83)
    - Japan, 1962 (Box 57, Folder 84)
    - Far East, 1964 April (Box 58, Folder 85)
    - Europe, 1964 (Box 58, Folder 86)
    - London, 1966 September-October (Box 58, Folder 87)
    - Mexico, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 88)
    - Europe, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 89)
    - France, 1968 October-Nov, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 90-91)
  - Miscellaneous, 1932-1971, undated, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 58, Folder 92-93)
- OVERSIZE, Series V
  - WRITINGS
    - The French Election of 1827: working papers, undated (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Strategic Intelligence for American World Policy: complete manuscript, chapters 1-5, 1947 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Strategic Intelligence for American World Policy: rejected pages from first manuscript, 1948 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Strategic Intelligence for American World Policy: 2nd draft, chapter 2, 1947 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - SUBJECT FILES
    - French history
      - French election, 1816-1824: graphs, undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - French election, 1827: graphs, undated (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - July Monarchy, 1831-1845: graphs, undated (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Intelligence
      - Cuban missile crisis: maps, 1963 (Box 59, Folder 8)
      - Research and Analysis Branch: diagram, 1943-1945 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - Autographs: William T. Sherman, undated (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Desk calendars, 1972-1974 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Photograph: given to Kent at a farewell party at the time of his retirement from the CIA, 1967 (Box 59, Folder 12)
- Additional Material, 1917-1991; Accession 1997-M-183
  Sherman Kent - 63
  This addition is composed of material donated by Mrs. Sherman Kent (Accessions 1992-M-014 and 1992-M-073) after processing was completed in 1990, as well as material that had been received prior to 1990 but not included in the 1990 processing project. The addition includes material similar in form and content to that previously processed, and it has, therefore, been arranged parallel to the original series structure, with correspondence at the beginning, followed by writings, subject files, and personal papers. Photographs are located at the end of the addition.
  The correspondence includes additional exchanges with family members and with personal friend William B. Kip and letters of congratulation on Kent's marriage in 1934. There are numerous letters to Kent from his brothers, Roger and William, and mother, Elizabeth Thacher Kent. The file for his wife, Elizabeth Gregory Kent, contains letters sent to him before their marriage and during Kent's tour of duty overseas in 1943-1944.
  Additional writings include manuscripts for both published and unpublished works of fiction and non-fiction. The files include drafts and a published copy of Kent's memoir, Reminiscences of a Varied Life. This brings to fruition Kent's autobiographical efforts, which are more fully documented in Boxes 53 and 54. There is also material on Kent's publication of Strategic Intelligence and a complete copy of the manuscript "Opals and Gold," which is a revision of the boys adventure story, "Gold and Opals." Earlier drafts are in Boxes 35 and 36.
  The bulk of subject files added concern intelligence; these include memoranda, reports, and notes which date from the termination of the United States Office of Strategic Services after World War II. Its Research and Analysis branch, to which Kent had belonged, was moved to the State Department and renamed IRIS, Interim Research and Intelligence Service, with Kent as its acting director. The papers document Kent's futile struggle to keep the intelligence contingent together as a unit; the State Department, instead, chose to assign individuals from the unit to different geographic branches.
  Personal papers include school materials of Sherman Kent and a few items concerning other members of the Kent family. There are also photographs of Sherman Kent taken during the 1960s and of Roger Kent in uniform during World War II.
  - Correspondence
    - A-K, 1934-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Arnold, Elizabeth Kent and family, 1933-1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Howard, Adeline Kent, 1942-1943, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Kent, Elizabeth Gregory, 1934, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Kent, Elizabeth, Thacher, 1932-1938, 1943-1945, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5-8)
    - Kent, Roger, 1931-1939, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9-13)
    - Kent, William, Jr., 1928-1942, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Kip-Wilder, Katrinka [correspondence of William B. Kip, including poem by William D. Kip re Richard Bond and Sherman Kent] 1926-1934, 1951, 1977, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - L-Z, 1935-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Writings
    - The French Election [notes] n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Opals and Gold"
      - pp. 1-76, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
      - pp. 77-138, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Reminiscences of a Varied Life
      - Draft chapters 1-45, 1983 Nov (Box 2, Folder 21-28)
      - Sanitized chapters 21-40, 1983 Nov (Box 2, Folder 29-30)
      - Questions on deletions, 1984 Jan (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Chapters 25-35 [rewritten], 1984 May (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
      - Chapter 32-35 [rewritten], May 1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Chapter 28-31, 35, 1984 Oct (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Chapter 42, "Villele Diary and Guizot Archive," 1984 (Box 3, Folder 36)